gaf.com 2019-06-15

# GAF | Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy

Effective date June 11, 2010 (last updated May 2019)  

##   
This Privacy Policy applies to our platforms.

This Privacy Policy describes how GAF Materials LLC d/b/a GAF (“we,” “us,” “our” or “ourselves”) treats the information we gather in connection with the digital platforms we operate and that link to this Privacy Policy. Our digital platforms include, but are not limited to, our Company website(s), product review tools or services, the GAF My Roof and Contractor Zone portals, GAF chat service(s), and mobile applications (“apps”). This Privacy Policy also applies to the information that we may collect via social media platforms and our electronic communications. 

By accessing or using our digital platforms, or registering for any of our product warranties or guarantees, you agree to this Privacy Policy. This includes changes that we may post here from time to time.

##  We collect information from and about you.

**Information you submit or post.**  We collect the information you provide to us, enter on our digital platforms, or post in public forums. This includes the information you post on our social media pages or on third party websites, information you provide when making purchases from us, and information provided to register for an account, warranty, guaranty, or portal. The information collected may include, but is not limited to, your name, address, phone number(s), email address(es), username, password, demographics (e.g., gender or age), graphics, and payment information.  

By providing information to us, you represent and warrant that you own or otherwise control all of the rights to the content that you provide; that the content is accurate; that use of the content you supply does not violate this policy and will not cause injury to any person or entity; and that you will indemnify us for all claims resulting from content you supply. We take no responsibility and assume no liability for any content provided by you or any third party.   

**Other Information.**  We, our service providers, and businesses that support our business operations, including, but not limited to, third party providers of advertising or analytics services, may use technologies like cookies and pixel tags to automatically collect information when you access our digital platforms or interact with our electronic communications. The information that we collect automatically or manually, may include technical information from or about your computer, mobile device or Wi-Fi network (including SSID and password for certain apps), DHCP, the browser you use, your search history, the number of times you visit our platforms, the device you use, identifiers associated with your device, your device’s operating system, the content you view on our digital platforms, the content you view immediately before and after using our digital platforms, product preferences, and the programs and services you use with us or others. We, our service providers, and third parties (e.g., network advertising companies) may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use our digital platforms.

We may obtain information about you from third parties. For example, our business partners may provide us with information about you.

##  Location Information.

Our apps may collect precise information about the location of your mobile device when location services are enabled on your device. We may use the information to provide you with information, promotions, or advertising relevant to your location. We do not share location information with third parties for their independent use without your consent.

## We use information as disclosed and described here.

We use information to provide you with services, including on our digital platforms or in connection with our products and apps, and to respond to your requests, inquiries, comments, and questions. We also use information to send you products you may want to purchase.

We use information to troubleshoot and improve our products and services, including our digital platforms. We may use the information we collect to customize your experience with us.

We use information for marketing purposes. For example, we might use the information we collect to send you information about products, services or special offers that we believe may interest you. This might include information about upcoming contests or promotions. We may use the information we collect to deliver advertisements based on your activities on our digital platforms and third party websites and apps. For example, if you view one of our products on our website, you may receive an online ad for that product or a related product on our digital platforms or on third party websites and apps.

We use information to communicate with you about your account or our relationship. For example, we might tell you about changes to our platforms or to your accounts. Or we might reach out to you and ask you to take a customer satisfaction survey.

We may use the information we collect to better understand the interests and preferences of our customers, people who use our digital platforms, and people who buy our products. For example, we may use information to generate and analyze aggregate statistics about how users interact with our digital platforms.

We may combine the information we collect. For example, we might combine information you give us with information we get from a public source. We might also combine information we collect from you with information we get from third parties. When we do so, we treat the combined information as disclosed in this Privacy Policy.

We use information as permitted by law and as otherwise disclosed to you. For example, we may use the information we collect to protect the rights and property of us, you, and others.

##    
We may share information with third parties. 

We will share information within our Company. We may share your information with our affiliates or subsidiaries. We may also share information with other related entities.

We will share information with third parties who perform services on our behalf, and the information provided may be used for any of the purposes set forth in this policy. For example, we may share your information with vendors. These vendors include companies that handle credit card processing and shipping, companies that provide us with data management services, companies that manage our digital platforms, and companies that manage our communications and perform market research for us.

We may share information with third party marketing partners. For example, we might share information with a company with whom we are running a joint promotion.

We may share information with online network advertisers and similar companies to facilitate the delivery of marketing communications on our digital platforms and thirdparty websites and apps. Those communications may include ads regarding our or others’ products based on your interests. We may use third party analytics providers that collect information about your use of our digital platforms to help us understand how people interact with those digital platforms.

We will share information if we think we have to in order to comply with the law or to protect ourselves. For example, we will share your information with legal authorities when we think it reasonable to do so. We may also share your information in situations where we think that our rights or the rights of our users or others are at risk.

We may share information with any successor to all or part of our business. We may share your information as part of or as reasonably necessary to proceed with a transfer of business assets.

We may share information for other reasons we may describe to you. And we may share aggregate information or information that does not reasonably identify you with third parties for any reason.

##  You have certain choices about sharing, marketing and tracking.

You can opt out of receiving our marketing emails. If you are a registered user, you can opt out of marketing emails by clicking [here](http://us.gaf.com/OptOut). You can also follow the instructions in any promotional message you get from us. Even if you opt out of getting marketing messages, we may still send you service-related announcements and transactional messages. In our mobile apps, you may be able to disable push notifications within the settings menu.

You may be able to control cookies on your device. Most web browsers give you the ability to control cookies. How you do so depends on the type of cookie. Certain browsers can be set to reject browser cookies. To control flash cookies you can go [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). Why? Because you cannot control flash cookies through your browser settings. If you choose to block cookies, you may not be able to take advantage of all aspects of our digital platforms.

In addition, you can learn about opting out of receiving interest-based ads from some or all participating companies by clicking [here](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

##  These digital platforms and children.

Our digital platforms are intended for people who are 13 years of age or older. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13 without permission from a parent or guardian. If you are a parent or legal guardian and think your child under 13 has given us information, you can email us at [privacy@gaf.com](mailto:privacy@gaf.com). You can also write to us at the address listed at the end of this policy. Please mark your inquiries “COPPA Information Request.”

Parents, you can learn more about how to protect children's privacy on-line [here](http://www.business.ftc.gov/privacy-and-security/childrens-privacy).

##  We use standard security measures.

Information submitted via the Internet is not 100% secure. We cannot promise that your use of our digital platforms will be completely safe. We encourage you to use caution when using the Internet. This includes not sharing your passwords.

We keep personal information as long as it is necessary or relevant for the practices described in this Privacy Policy. We also keep information as otherwise required by law.

##  We store information in the United States.

By using our digital platforms, you consent to have your personal data transferred to the United States. Our digital platforms are subject to U.S. laws, which may not afford the same level of protection as those in your country.

##  We may link to other sites or have third party services on our site we don’t control.

If you click on a link to a third party website, you will be taken to websites we do not control. This includes social networks. Please read the privacy policies of any third party website that you visit. Your use of those websites will not be governed by this Privacy Policy, and we are not responsible for those third party practices. Our platforms may also have third party content or services we do not control. This may include passive tracking tools.

##  Your California privacy rights

If you reside in California and have provided personally identifiable information to us, you may request information once per calendar year about our disclosures of certain categories of your personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us in writing at the address listed below.

##  Feel free to contact us if you have any questions.

If you have any questions about this policy, please email us at: [Privacy@gaf.com](mailto:privacy@gaf.com)

You can also call or write us at:   

> GAF Materials LLC d/b/a GAF  
>  1 Campus Drive  
>  Parsippany, NJ 07054  
> 888-532-5767

##  We may update this Policy.

From time to time we may change our privacy policies. We will notify you of any material changes to this Privacy Policy as required by law. We will also post an updated copy on our website. Please check our website periodically for updates.
